<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sarah Lecinski</title><link>https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/</link><description>Recent content on Sarah Lecinski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Education</title><link>https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/posts/education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/posts/education/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="phd-in-biophysics-2023">PhD in biophysics, 2023&lt;/h3>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> Cellular stress and optical microscopy
Physics of Life group
University of York (UK)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/posts/publication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/posts/publication/</guid><description>An easy acess to published papers in ORCiD
PhD project highlight I investigated the role of macromolecular crowding (confinement effects) In the budding yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae during stress episodes such as osmotic stress and nutrient starvation. To monitor crowding in the cell I used a combination of molecular biosensors (FRET technology), confocal and Slimfield super-resolution light microscopy technique as physical tools. I optimised a cellular model with yeast strains engineered for the controlled expression of trackable (down to single molecule level) fluorescently tagged cytoplasmic aggregates.</description></item><item><title>Science outreach</title><link>https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/posts/outreaches/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://slecinski.github.io/sarah-lecinski/posts/outreaches/</guid><description>Public outreaches are activities I enjoy doing during py PhD ( see below), I also present here access to couple of video games I adapted, a bit of a neardy hobby But I can see a potential for public outreaches.
🕹️ Video games I enjoyed learning to code for image analysis purpose. With some notion of coding I had fun giving a try to video game programation. All games are adapted from open-sourced video games, All coded in Lua Language.</description></item></channel></rss>